Keleen, when you think about your first
day here, what's it like just to be in
the building and uh kind of have it soak
up the moment and I have follow up for
Demeco. Thank you.
Uh yeah, I mean that's first off a
blessing. Obviously you dream of this
your whole life. Just getting an
opportunity to play in the NFL. That's a
lifelong dream. So, you get that
opportunity. I'm so grateful that it's
you know the Houston Texans and I get to
come in here and meet all these
wonderful people that I've met and it's
a great it's a great place. You can tell
the people are genuine and I'm just so
excited to get to work.
And for Demeco, think about watching the
video and you're talking about this is
the kind of player we need. You want
toughness on offense. So, just see if
you could expand on that a little bit.
Thank you.
And we're we're excited you know for
Keleen to be a part of our team, right?
Because he represents you know what
we're about and that's about playing
tough, playing physical. It's about
finishing and for anyone that's watched
this young man's tape, you know the
highlight of his tape is how he finishes
plays. It's something that's innate,
something that's in him and something
that we truly believe in here. And I
know he's going to bring that toughness
and that physicality and that finish
mindset, the relentless mindset that we
look for. He's bringing that to our
team. So, that's why we're fired up to
have him.
This is for Nick and I guess maybe
Demeco a little bit. Nick, last night
you mentioned some of the elements of
the grade that you had on Keleen that
were you know were really high. Can you
kind of reveal without revealing too
much about those elements specifically?
Yeah, anytime you're creating a profile
on a player, there's obviously the
physical components on the field and
then you're looking at some of the
intangible items that are going to apply
to the player from a coachability from
an intelligence standpoint, football
character,
instincts, toughness, overall
competitiveness, the way Demeco alluded
to it. So, those are things like we
prioritize in this program. We
prioritize and every player is evaluated
based on that criteria and Keleen like
stood head and shoulders above a lot of
other players. So, that's a part of the
evaluation. So, when you combine that
with what you see on the tape, then you
put the profile of the player together
and say like this is what a Houston and
Texan football player looks like. So, we
take a lot of pride and we put a lot of
value in that. Like you guys have been
around our team like and we've talked
about this. You win with people and you
win with mental and physical toughness.
That's what this league is about. So, in
order to be physical, in order to play
with mental physical toughness, you have
to add players to your team that possess
those qualities. So, if you say that's
what you're about, well then it's our
responsibility to go out there and find
it and like nobody epitomizes more that
more than Keleen, which is why he's
sitting in the chair next to us.
Keleen,
you were speaking yesterday about right
here. Jonathan Alexander, Houston
Chronicle. Nice to meet you.
Uh you were speaking yesterday about
kind of your mindset. Other people have
described you as kind of like playing
with like a nasty mindset. Um like you
finish people. But I'm just curious how
you adopted that. Where that came from,
what what influences that? Is it is it
your upbringing, where you came from?
What influences that?
I mean I think you can point to a lot of
lot of areas. I think I'm just first and
foremost like a competitor. I just love
to compete on everything I do and I
think if you're a true competitor, you
want to finish like as an offensive
lineman, you want to put the dude in the
dirt. I mean you want to play to the
echo of the whistle.
You want to compete at a high level and
you want to be the best about it. So, I
think that's just you know just the
competitor in me. I've always had that
fire about me. So, I think that's where
it comes from.
Uh this is for Nick and Demeco.
Obviously, whenever a player gets
picked, there's always talk well this
team wanted him before. So, you had to
go up and get him. How do you prepare
for that? Like maybe leading up to it
where you talk about acting stuff up and
then in the moment and how hectic can it
be when you want a guy and you
anticipate that maybe team in front of
you would want the same guy? Yeah, it's
really about organization and
preparation and then capitalizing the
opportunity when it presents itself. So,
I mean Demeco and I talk I would say I
mean 40 times a day. So, we're talking
about players, we're talking about
different scenarios. He probably wants
me out of his office plenty of the time.
But you're always going through
different scenarios and in our
situation, say once we got into the like
16, 17, 18, 19, 20, you start to look at
all right, who are the players that are
available? Who are some of the players
that we would consider taking and you
kind of create some buckets. And then as
you go through, again, we don't really
know what other teams are going to do.
Like you try to as best you can make an
estimation and look at the the roster.
Hey, there's some players that they
might be interested in. It doesn't mean
that for sure they're going to be you're
going to be interested in the same
player. And then we look at it through
the lens of in the end, what's the best
thing for the Houston Texans? We can't
worry about what other teams are doing.
They're going to make their decisions we
have to make our decisions independent
of when anybody else is doing. So, in
terms of how chaotic it it's really not.
It's pretty fluid. It's ongoing. And we
just kind of react and we're ready to go
and if you do a trade, you make a trade
and you pick the player. If you can't
consummate the trade, then you prepare
for the next opportunity in front of
you. So, we're pretty consistent. It'll
be no different here tonight when we get
started here in a few hours. Keleen,
have you had a chance to I know you
haven't been in town long, but have you
had a chance to meet any other members
of the offense since you landed in
Houston?
Uh yes, sir. Uh C.J. Stroud came by,
text me. Will text me. Um and C.J.
Stroud came by the hotel. We talked for
a long time. He's a great human being
first and foremost, but obviously we all
know how he how he is out there on the
grass and he's
he's made of the right stuff. So, he's a
he's a great dude, man. Just great for
him to come up there and take time to
come talk to me.
Uh Keleen, right in here. Earlier today,
it was said by by Coach Keely that you
met with Cole Popovich before the draft.
Um what were those conversations like
and what did you think about the overall
offensive approach that he was kind of
talking with you about? Yeah, I mean I I
really love my time with Coach Pop. He
put me through a lot of the things that
you know he's looking for and you know
in terms of how he's going to throw
hands, all them all them details kind of
thing and you know different than what I
did in college, but you know I just
soaked it in. Just try to take the
coaching. He's he's there to coach me
and see what I had, see how I was moving
and I I really enjoyed the time and the
Zoom I had with him just talking ball
and I loved it.
Uh Demeco, um when you were looking at
Keleen's film and and and you were
obviously liking what you were seeing,
what what what
what did you and and Nick Keely envision
for him?
Uh for me, when I'm I'm watching the
film of all these offensive lineman, I'm
studying a lot of different guys and
when I put on his tape, I typed in the
word swarm.
And that's what it that's what I saw on
tape. That's the type of player that I
saw and the envision is he can he play
multiple spots on the interior part of
the offensive line. Though he spent a
lot of time at right guard. He snapped
the ball at senior bowl, did a really
good job of that. Smart young man,
bright young man. We're just happy to
work with him. See may the best five
guys go out there and help us win some
games. He's ready to compete. He's
talked about how he loves to compete.
That's how he gained his edge and that's
what we're all about. I saw that
competitor mindset. I saw it jump off of
the tape and that made it an easy
choice. And for us and for me, we're
drafting, you see a guy you want. That's
why I love working with Nick. We see a
guy we want. We see a guy who fits our
building, fits what we're about, fits
our culture. Let's go get the guy, add
him to our team.
Uh this is for Demeco and Nick. When
when y'all um hired Popovich as the
offensive line coach, what what was it
that y'all liked about Cole Popovich and
is did do is this is it safe to say that
the what we've seen with this offensive
line is kind of
a significant impact of his with with
the with the turnover and everything? Go
ahead, Nick. Yeah, I mean hiring Cole,
the one thing in the interviewing
process like Cole is a a brilliant
coach. He's very smart guy and he's not
just offensive line driven. Like he's
very thoughtful in seeing the entire
picture of the offensive line, right?
And how it all fits together. He's very
thoughtful in making sure, hey, which
guys do I need? What do they do well?
And he he does a really good job. You
guys ever get the opportunity to see him
work in his individuals and how he takes
the time to coach the guys up on all the
fine, small details that's really
important for an offensive lineman and
it's him being detailed, being thorough
as a coach and never
stuck on what he's always done. He's
always trying to help his players,
always trying to improve his players and
to me that's the signs of a really good
coach. He's a excellent communicator,
does a really great job on game day as
well. We need to make adjustments. Cole
is the guy who sees it, can make the
adjustments and get us in the right
right situation. So, he's all the things
you want in a coach.
Nick and I I guess to an extent Demeco,
how much of what happens on day one
changes what you would maybe expect to
do on day two? And I know you guys moved
back about 20 spots in the third round,
but also you know now you have Keleen,
offensive lineman. Would you you know
still be expected to maybe draft an
offensive lineman as well? How much
changes from after things are done in
the first round to the second round?
Always open for business on anything.
Doesn't necessarily take it just because
you select one player doesn't
necessarily take you out of either a
player or a position. Like we'll go back
to what we've kind of done today is look
at the board and said all right, here's
certain players graded at a certain
level. What are opportunities? We're
scheduled to pick right now at 38 with
five or six picks in.
What are options? Who are the players
that we've identified? If they're
available, will we pick them? Great. If
not, we'll move back and then we're
scheduled to pick at 59 and then 91 or
whatever it is right now. So, we'll just
follow the board, look at our grades. In
the end, we always go back to our
grades. What do we say about the player?
What have our scouts said? What have the
coaches said? And then just kind of work
ourselves around the board and try to
make good smart decisions. I mean we
didn't go into the draft last year
anticipating we were going to draft
Jaylen Hyatt, but that's the way the
board fell. So, we took both players.
So, if there's an opportunity to draft
another offensive lineman that makes
sense, we'll certainly consider it.
We're not going to rule it out because
you really never know when you're going
to need these players and what the
overall constitution of the team is
going to look like. I mean, we can't sit
here today and say, "Well, we know what
it's going to look like in September."
It could change. So, we're always
planning for what's in front of us, but
we're going to add good players with the
right mentality, with the right mindset,
let the players ultimately sort itself
out, and then if we got to make some
decisions at some point, then we'll make
the decision we feel are best for the
team.
Keilan, uh Brent Key today was telling
me that there was a conditioning test
and
guys were, you know, trying to get
through it. It was it was a tough one.
And you were literally pushing your
teammates and yelling. Do you remember
that? Was that this year or last year?
Just What can you tell me about that?
And I have a follow-up.
Uh yes, sir. I mean, I definitely
remember that, but it was just who I am
every day. Uh no different conditioning
test, first day,
um winter jacket drills, inside run.
It's just, "Hey, you competitor. You
want all your teammates to be wired the
same way you are and uh get after it."
So, you're going to push some guys to
their limit and you hope that they push
you to your limit. Iron sharpens iron,
so.
You still watch even though after you
were done, you were watching the tape
and critiquing the practice stuff. He
said that you were kind of going back
and wonder, you know, was the standard,
you know, still going the way you wanted
it to with your younger teammates? Yeah,
I mean, there's a lot of new new faces
in there on the O-line over there at
Georgia Tech. So, you want to watch the
tape. You know, I'm going into practice,
don't know a lot of the guys, so a lot
of new faces over there. So, I just want
to see what they're about, see how they
play the game. And obviously, when you
go to practice, I'm going to, "Hey, if I
see something on tape, I'm going to let
them know like, 'Hey, I think this, yada
yada.'" So, you just you want them to
You I would love to be a sponge and you
want them to supposed to soak it up.
Lastly, uh
he called you an underrated athlete. And
they were saying that you ran in the
4.9s. You were actually disappointed to
run, I think it was 5.05 at the at the
combine. Uh and you basketball, that
stuff. What does your background in
those sports and other thing kind of say
about you as an athlete? Thank you.
Uh yes, sir. I mean, I think I'm a a
good athlete, obviously. You know, I
don't want to toot my own horn, but I
think I move well. Um grew up didn't
play offensive line till I got to
college, so grew up playing tight end
and D-line. Um played all sorts of
sports, played basketball, threw shot
put, so you know,
jack of all trades kind of deal.
Keilan, I wanted to ask you a little bit
more about um what you were saying
earlier when CJ came by.
Um did y'all break bread? What did you
make of him coming over to the hotel and
and and what can you tell us about, I
guess, the general message?
Yeah, I mean, I think first of all, I
was just excited. Um
you know, you could tell he's a leader.
He's made like I said, he's made of the
right stuff. So, he just wanted to come
over there and just hey, congratulate
me. Um just, you know, welcome me and uh
just I mean, just talking life, you
know? Nothing special. Uh just guys
being guys, just talking ball and
wishing me luck. And he said, "Hey, if
you need anything, I'm here for you."
So, what you want your quarterback
Keilan, you were a player that entered
the transfer portal and went to Georgia
Tech. And you mentioned that you didn't
play offensive line till you got to
college. Can you talk about your
relationship with Brent Key and what he
meant to be able to help you get to
where you are today?
Yeah, I mean, Brent Key's a great ball
coach, great man, just what he stood for
at Georgia Tech, um the way he ran the
program. I think, you know, that's the
way it should be ran. It was built on
toughness. It was just built on how we
were going to be committed, how we were
going work with your teammates. It was
it was ran the right way. And obviously,
he's a O-line guy, so he's always
getting his nose in the offensive line
in D. And you know, he just developed me
in the right way. He'd always bring me
in his office, talk life first and
foremost, and then he'd be like, "Hey,
fix this, fix this." So, he he's a
really good ball coach and he's, you
know, I can credit him for for where I'm
sitting today.
Pedro Hernandez, Televisa.
Keilan, with the Houston Texans being so
close to Mexico, there's a huge fan base
over there in Mexico and Monterrey. Any
message to more of your international
fans outside of Houston?
Heck yeah, I mean, love all my fans.
Let's get Let's get after it this year.
Um let's play some football and I Let's
just Let's swarm. Let's go Let's go win
some games.
All right.
All right, thank you
Thanks.